<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mobile on Alessio Basso</title>
    <link>/tags/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mobile on Alessio Basso</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Great retail experience</title>
      <link>/2020/04/aeonapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/04/aeonapp/</guid>
      <description>I like a lot to wander around a grocery store, browsing the shelves and thinking at the tasty dishes I could turn all those ingredients into. One thing I don&amp;rsquo;t like is queuing up at the cashier, which usually is a long endeavour as people (at least here in HK) expect the cashier to both scan their items and bag them, collect the payment, etc etc&amp;hellip;
So I was very pleased to find out about a feature in the mobile app of a known supermarket chain in Hong Kong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banking in the Age of Social Media</title>
      <link>/2017/05/banking-in-the-age-of-social-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/banking-in-the-age-of-social-media/</guid>
      <description>I happened to be in Guangzhou last week, and attending an interesting round table discussion during a banking technology event.
One of the guests was from WeBank, sharing his experience working in a technology company that happens to hold a banking license in China.
He shared the fact that they started as a technology company even before they had the license, developing a banking platform that is now used by 8 local banks in China in a BaaS (Banking as a Service) model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cathay Pacific, mobile app</title>
      <link>/2014/12/cxapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 12:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/12/cxapp/</guid>
      <description>Few days ago, Cathay Pacific released its new mobile app.
I downloaded the android version, and gave it a try. TL;DR? It&amp;rsquo;s better than it used to be, looks more modern, but there are a number of bugs still open, and questionable design chooices have been made. Here are a few comments.
 Two different loading spinners: why?
  Page transitions (see below an example of the language selection) are ok, but the &amp;ldquo;back&amp;rdquo; button should animate from left to right, not right to left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Website&#39;s restyling</title>
      <link>/2014/10/cx/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 09:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/10/cx/</guid>
      <description>Last Sunday, Cathay Pacific launched a new restyling for its website. It looks modern while still elegant, and — most important, given the lacking of a mobile app to book flights — it looks good on a mobile.
I write “looks” good, because when you start using it, lots of small issues becomes evident. Let’s start from the beginning.
 When I first open the home page, everything looks good.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>